

ENGINEER FRONT END

CONTACT

509.868.9102



mccombsmariem@gmail.com



www.linkedin.com/in/mariemccombs



Houston, TX

PROFILE

Passionate about technology, innovation, and modern web design with an overall experience of 4 years as a Front End Engineer. I have honed my talent in the field of technology by working for multiple types of industries and by rising to each challenge. I'm looking for an environment where I can continue to build my knowledge and skills while contributing to the overall success of my team and company.

EDUCATION

CERTIFICATE

Full Stack Web Development

University of Texas at Austin 2017

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE

Chemistry and Biochemistry Eastern Washington University

2005 - 2009

SOCIAL MEDIA

GITHUB

github.com/Bronzeowl

WEBSITE

bronzeowl.github.io/mariemccombs/

SKILLS

TECHNICAL

HTML, CSS, SASS, MangoDB, Express.js, React.js, Node.js, Bootstrap, JavaScript, Git, Firebase, Heroku, Sequel Pro, MySQL, PHP, Wordpress, API, Responsive Design, UI/UX

EXPERIENCE

FRONT END ENGINEER

DISCOVERY INC | January 2022 - Present

- Built advertising products to drive traffic to client's websites
- Generated custom sweepstakes to work in conjunction with third-pay forms
- Independently developed interactive and animated articles
- Assisted with content management for the corporate site

FRONT END DEVELOPER

SNAPPY KRAKEN | November 2018 - August 2021

- Collaborated with the product and design team remotely to build responsive products with marketing driven UI/UX
- Created various types of products such as landing pages and emails
- Trained lower-level employees in basic coding
- Provided prompt and effective troubleshooting for issues with products

FRONT END DEVELOPER

LANDRY'S INC | February 2018 - November 2018

- Worked with the marketing team to manage content for 50-60 sites across various industries
- Successfully self-managed during independent work while also contributing during collaborative team work
- Helped architect solutions for new feature and design requests
- Gained experience with various CMS products including Wordpress



MARIE MCCOMBS FRONT END ENGINEER

SKILLS

PERSONAL

Problem Solving

Teamwork

Collaboration

Adaptability

Creativity

Attention to Detail

Communication

PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT

UX Design

NYU Continuing Education 2021

ACHIEVEMENTS

- Pioneered position at Snappy Kraken by defining the developer role for the product team and gained new skills with evolving responsibilities
- Successfully self-managed during independent work while also contributing during collaborative team work
- Completed UX Design course at NYU Continuing Education
- Gained proficiency with HTML, SASS and Bootstrap
- Proved integral in a team at Snappy Kraken that created valuable marketing products for advisors to attract and maintain clientele